You think I left because I stopped caring, that I was looking for excuses to go.
You couldn't be more wrong, but that truth you'll never let yourself know,
because when you sit down to think about it, it all makes sense to you.
Of course, I messed it up, the feeling seems like nothing new.
You write a list of all your failures, a list of changes to make,
a list of how you can't give love so it would be too wrong of you to take.
But you're on my list of people to pray for, the list of people I wish to be well.
You're the top of the damn list for people, of people for whom I easily found.
You sit down and it makes sense to you.
To be loved isn't something you choose, you think yourself undeserving of it,
but to me, you're still a muse.
An aspiration to something better, a loud wish into the earth,
to be soulmates in every lifetime, even if you forgot.
In this one, for what it's worth.
You think that I left, but every part of me stays.
Anyways, you write a list of all your failures, you're successful to me anyways.
Despite your self-doubting, despite your damn list,
you've recorded every single one of your faults.
I write poetry to convince you that your beauty still exists.
But love is not mutual destruction.
Love cannot change your mind.
I think you're heaven on earth.
You think I'm somebody else's to find.
I say you're the winning lottery ticket.
You say you're just a rusted penny on the floor.
I say I've never seen you that way.
So you say you never want to see me again anymore.
Sometimes.
Some days.
Some months in between.
Then I get a text message that I pretend not to have seen.
You know, there's a mailbox in my mind replaying voicemails I never sent
with an infinite amount of storage full of words you thought I never meant.
from my new book, A Magnificently Ordinary Romance, available in bookstores and online now.